Hyecheol (Jerry) Jang

45 N Orchard St. Madison, WI, 53715, United States of America

□ (+1) 608-770-1154 | ► hyecheol.jang@wisc.edu | □ hyecheol123 (GitHub) | □ jhyecheol (LinkedIn)

Summary.

Interested in finding optimized solution using Cloud (MS Azure) and writing understandable codes. Passionate about new technologies/languages/solutions. Experienced in **backend**/frontend development, deployment/operation, and **project management**.

Open to internships/co-op opportunities as a software developer or solution architect. Expect to graduate in May. 2024.

Education

University of Wisconsin-Madison

Madison, WI, United States

Jul. 2018 - Current

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE; DOUBLE MAJOR IN STATISTICS; MINOR IN ENTREPRENEURSHIP

- **GPA: 3.89/4.00**, Dean's List in 3 out of 4 semesters
- · Library Technology Student Assistant at College Library, Memorial Library, and CALS Computing Lab
- Military Service in Busan, South Korea (Oct. 2020 Jul. 2022)

Work Experience

DIRECTOR OF TECHNOLOGY (VOLUNTEER)

Korean-American Scientists and Engineers Association - Wisconsin Chapter (Nonprofit Organization)

Madison, WI, United States

Dec. 2018 - Current

- · Responsible for developing and maintaining organization's website and other practical applications for management, events, and membership services
- Project: KSEA-Wisc Website (Jul. 2019 Nov. 2019) Project Manager & Lead Developer
 Designed and developed a website for general information, membership services, and event notifications
 Creatively designed/developed/launched the organization's website to run at zero cost using HTML, CSS, Jekyll, GitHub Pages, and Cloudflare CDN
- **Project: Event Ticket System** (Aug. 2022 Current) Project Manager & Lead Developer
 Building automated event ticket generation (QR code) and ticket validation for admission (Est. Release: Jan. 2023)
 Using Azure Function, Azure Blob Storage (for static website hosting), Azure Cosmos DB, Cloudflare (CDN), and React Native
- Project: KSEA-Wisc Website Version 2 (Sep. 2022 Current) Project Manager & Lead Developer Enhancing the website by adding an admin portal using Next.js and MS Azure (Est. Release: Jan. 2023)

uniQon Seoul, South Korea

CHIEF TECHNICAL OFFICER (FULL-TIME)

May. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Closely collaborated with CEO to build concrete business plans; traveled frequently for business meetings
- Recruited and trained interns and software developers.
- · Implemented IT infrastructure and remote working environment with Microsoft Teams, Jira, and GitHub
- Project: uniQon: Mentoring System for High School Students (Jun. 2020 Oct. 2020) Project Manager
 Elaborated an idea of a system that provides prospective applicants with college application data and mentor information
 Designed the overall system architecture; estimated the project timelines and set up milestones.
 Allocated the resources and team members workload; Adopted an agile workflow process (Scrum) with weekly feedback to team/individuals
 Involved in early-stage development using NodeJS with TypeScript and MongoDB to develop and operate API server, web page, and admin portal

Projects

BusanDevelopers Event Calendar

Busan, South Korea

PROJECT MANAGER & LEAD DEVELOPER

• Effectively divided the project into smaller milestones, and managed/collaborated with one back-end developer and

Aug. 2021 - Jan. 2022

- Effectively divided the project into smaller milestones, and managed/collaborated with one back-end developer and one front-end developer
- Used React (MUI), NodeJS, Azure Cosmos DB, ExpressJS, and ReDoc and manually set TypeScript React environment using ESLint, WebPack, and Babel
- Released on Jan. 2022; Source Code: github.com/BusanDevelopers

Cloudflare Public Dynamic IP Update Script

Madison, WI, United States

Jul. 2019 - Aug. 2019

• Built a script to update server's dynamic ip address to Cloudflare (DDNS)

• 50+ GitHub Star; Source Code: github.com/hyecheol123/Cloudflare-Public-Dynamic-IP-Update

Honors & Awards _

Third Place, 2022 Al·Blockchain Idea Competition, Busan Metropolitan City, South Korea

Skills

DEVELOPER

Programming Language: TypeScript, JavaScript, Java, SQL, R, C, C++, Python, Bash

Cloud Service: Microsoft Azure **AZ-900, AI-900, DP-900 Certified**, Naver Cloud Platform, AWS, DigitalOcean (and other VPS providers)

DB: Azure SQL, Azure Cosmos DB, mariaDB, mongoDB, redis

Web Development: Express, React, Redux, MUI (React Library), Next.js, Socket.IO, WebSockets, HTML, CSS **Misc**: Linux/UNIX Server (Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS), Git, Cloudflare, PyTorch, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Scrum

Microsoft Office Specialist (Microsoft 365/Office 2019): Associate (Excel, Powerpoint, Word), Expert (Excel Expert, Access Expert)

Language: English (Advanced), Korean (Native)